

Mohamed Okaily

Nationality: Egyptian Date of birth: 1996 Phone number: (+49) 015906455376

▼ Email address: mo.okaily01@gmail.com

WhatsApp Messenger: +49 015906455376

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mokaily

■ Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/mokaily

Behance: https://www.behance.net/mokaily

Website: https://www.mokaily.com/

• Home: Marburg (Germany)

ABOUT ME

I bring over 5 years of expertise as a Flutter developer, coupled with proficiency in UI/UX design. Additionally, I delve into junior data science. I enjoy solving and creating innovative solutions for complex problems, and collaborating with other developers and designers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Flutter Developer

Mein Paul [05/2023 - Current]

City: Kempten

Country: Germany

Contributing to Mein PAUL, an integrated system for tax consultants, enabling remote work and improving client experience. Assisted in building and optimizing the system for both web and mobile platforms.

Flutter Developer

MINTANO [09/2022 - 04/2023]

City: Dusseldorf
Country: Germany

I led the creation of our multifaceted photobooth app, merging photos, videos, and AR interactions for unique brand/event engagement. I contributed to both front-end and back-end development to ensure seamless user experiences. I led the creation of our multifaceted photobooth app, merging photos, videos, and AR interactions for unique brand/event engagement. I contributed to both front-end and back-end development to ensure seamless user experiences.

Flutter Developer

Bavest Technologies [01/2022 - 09/2022]

City: Karlsruhe **Country:** Germany

I enhanced the application by introducing significant features, including advanced analytical interactions, screening capabilities, and more. This application serves as an investment research platform tailored for private investors.

Front-End Developer

TEQNEIA [09/2020 - 04/2021]

City: Giza

Country: Egypt

Led front-end team management and support across multiple applications at the software house. Held responsibility for UI/UX functions as well.

Front-End Developer, UI/UX developer

Egyptian Railway station [11/2019 - 08/2020]

City: Cairo
Country: Egypt

I was responsible for two out of six projects within a plan for the rebuild the railway system in Egypt, under the auspices of the Ministry of Transportation and the supervision of the Egyptian Armed Forces.

RECOMMENDATIONS

CTO

Name: Tobias Timm

Phone number: (+49) 021178178935

Email: team@mintano.com

Mohamed is a very quick learner and is able to acquire new skills swiftly. He seamlessly became part of our team. His behavior towards his colleagues was exemplary at all times. We highly recommend Mohamed to any future employer without reservation and we are confident he will be a valuable asset to any company - startup or corporation. The entire team wishes Mohamed much success in his endeavors and the very best in the future.

Link: https://media.licdn.com/dms/document/media/D4E2DAQFZGvHAQScxXw/profile-treasury-document-pdf-analyzed/0/1681391741620?e=1695859200&v=beta&t=jGEztWyXwwpQA_fVU78u9EqPL4qA0X1u_NSA03CXiHE

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Masters of Data Science

Philipps Universität Marburg [2023 – Current]

City: Marburg
Country: Germany

Website: https://www.uni-marburg.de/de/studium/studienangebot/master/m-datasc

Data Science Nanodegree

Udacity [17/12/2022]

Website: https://graduation.udacity.com/confirm/3HSRQZ7T

The Udacity Data Science Nanodegree, in collaboration with IBM, covers essential data skills, machine learning, big data tech, and advanced topics like deep learning. It culminates in a hands-on capstone project.

Bachelor in Computer Science

Ahram Canadian University [10/2015 – 07/2019]

Country: Egypt

Website: https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C4D2DAQFn96q1nd_cUg/profile-treasury-image-

shrink 800 800/0/1643926459919?

<u>e=1696190400&v=beta&t=cPbOcIMz2ehwGelVkEHLR89mwTkxUcNB4YPaPLWPH0E</u>

Thesis: Churn Prediction

• Graduation Project: Using artificial intelligence AI to improve predictive models accuracy. • Publication: "Deep Neural Network Model for Churn Prediction" at the 4th International Undergraduate Research Conference (IUGRC-2019).

PUBLICATIONS

Deep Neural Network Model for Customer Churn Prediction

[2019]

1027-IUGRC-FULL

Customer Churn prediction (CPP) is one of the most critical issues for the prediction of customer behavior for excommerce systems. It is when businesses are able to predict the clients are at risk of churn. This paper introduces a new churn prediction model that utilizing Deep Neural Networks DNN to predict the churn customers of telecom company dataset. The dataset (Telco Customer Churn) is obtained from Kaggle Datasets containing records of customers' activities within time, each row represents a customer with its attributes, and the raw data contains 7043 rows and 21 columns. In The proposed model, the churn dataset is filtered and normalized in the first phase to prepare it for training using Artificial Neural Networks and optimizing using Adam optimizer until reaching to the best accuracy. The experimental results obtained show that the accuracy of the proposed model is satisfactory. This paper demonstrates a comparative analysis between the proposed models and other churn prediction models. In addition, the comparative results show that the proposed model is a promising prediction system for churn.

DIGITAL SKILLS

App Development

flutter Developer / Dart programing language / Html, Java, CSS / Firebase: Firestore, FirebaseAuth, Firestorage, RealTime database

App Managing Tools

Git / Postman / Devops: Docker, Jenkins / RESTful api / CI /CD / Github / Kubernetes, Docker-Swarm

Data Science

Data Science | Data Collection, Data Processing, Data Analysis, Data Visualisation / Data Gathering / Data Processing / Data Visualization / Data Analysis / Python (PyROOT, RDataFrame; ML: Keras, TensorFlow)

UI/UX

adobe xd / Adobe Photoshop, illustrator, Al

Architectures

MVVM / MVC / Clean Architecture